SOFÍA DE OLIVEIRA RICO

Customer Service Agent

+34 684 140 160

sofia-rico.github.io

Berlin, Germany



My professional road has been marked by 3 main points: Customer Service, Professional-Spanish Tutoring and Academic Research.

I'm deeply interested in how **Society's needs** are created and how they change, that's why I decided to study Political Sciences and Law and started to reflect those facts into **statistical reports**: qualitative-and-quantitative Content Analysis, journalistic articles and essays. To do so, I'm used to handling social databases as well as Social and Mass Media content comparisons and personal interviews. I always try to learn and improve, personally and professionally, and being able to **synthesize** different data and knowledge in a single project might be **one of my strongest points**.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Customer Service Agent

SAINT GOBAIN Materials and Solutions

2020, Madrid

ONLINE orientation and solution offering Call Center Representative Administrative tasks and reports (Excel, Word) HR coordination tasks (E-COORDINA)

Customer Service & Care Representative

2018 - 2019, Madrid

SEUR International Shipping

Call Center Agent - orientation and solution offering Administrative tasks and reports (Excel)

Receptionist and Administrative Assistant

2018, Madrid

MEDIAPRO TV Producer

Director's meeting assistant Call Centre representative

Internal HR bills, payroll and benefits ONLINE tool - Administrative assistant

Spanish (ELE) Teacher

2019, Madrid

Vamos, Madrid language Academy

A1-C2 Levels, Groups from 3-15, Kids & Adults

Freelance Spanish Teacher (Online)

2017 - Current

Spanish for Business (B1-C1 levels). Special focus on Public Speech for Mass Media and Political Conferences (EU Parliament in Brussels)

Spanish language - ONLINE lessons (A1-C1). Several students from the UK, Germany, Turkey, Oman and Saudi Arabia.

CERTIFICATES

Social Media Marketing HubSpot Academy	2020
Content Marketing HubSpot Academy	2020
Development project management Inter-American Development Bank (IDBX)	2020

Autonomous Teacher (DADIC) Cervantes Institute

DELE (Spanish international exams) examiner

2019

ABOUT ME

Nationality: Spain Birth Place: Madrid Birth Year: 1995 Marital Status: Single Driving Licence: B

Availability: Full Time & Immediately

SKILLS

Technical

Microsoft Office Pack:

Excel / Word / Powerpoint

IOS-Apple Tools:

Pages / Numbers

Professional

✓ Analytical skills

✓ Organized & Commited

✓ Detail-oriented

Punctual & Efficient

Resolutive & Methodological

▼ Team player & Emphatic

✓ Great work under pressure

Always willing to learn and improve

EDUCATION

Double Bachelor's Degree in Law & Political Sciences and Administration

University of Granada, Spain 2013 - 2019

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

Cervantes Institute

English (Professional)

Portuguese (B1)

github.com/sofia-rico in linkedin.com/in/sofiarico